Finding Aid of the UW-Milwaukee College of Letters & Science Records, 1948-2014
University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee Libraries, Archives Department
- Records, 1948-2014, UWM Archival Collection 1; 73.9 cubic ft. (83 boxes)
  - 1. Subject Files, 1948-2014
    - Ten-Year Plans
      - 1970-1980 (Box 30, Folder 19)
      - 1972-1982 (Box 30, Folder 20-22)
      - 1973-1983
        - Departmental Reports (Box 30, Folder 23-24)
        - Faculty Task Forces (Box 30, Folder 25)
        - Process of Preparation (Box 30, Folder 26)
        - Task Force Reports (Box 30, Folder 27)
      - 1974-1984 (Box 30, Folder 28)
    - Tenure Task Force, 1974-1975 (Box 30, Folder 29)
    - Town Hall of Milwaukee Program, 1963 (Box 30, Folder 30)
    - Transitions, 1996-2000 (Box 30, Folder 31)
    - Twenty Credit Rule, 1957 (Box 30, Folder 32)
    - Ukrainian Language Courses, 1973-1981 (Box 30, Folder 33)
    - UN Summer Seminar, 1984-1985 (Box 30, Folder 34)
    - Underachiever Project, 1963-1967 (Box 30, Folder 35)
    - Undergraduate Affairs Committee, 1972 (Box 30, Folder 36)
    - Undergraduate Instruction Handbook, 1981 (Box 78, Folder 6)
    - Undergraduate Language Instruction Committee, 1972-1973 (Box 30, Folder 37)
    - Undergraduate Studies Committee, 1971 (Box 30, Folder 38)
    - University Art Museum
      - 1982-1985 (Box 30, Folder 39)
      - Art Museum Task Force, Working Documents, 1995 (Box 81, Folder 9)
      - Final Report, 1995-1996 (Box 82, Folder 1)
      - Related Documents, 1992-1998 (Box 82, Folder 2)
      - Rosenberg Collection, 1974-1975 (Box 82, Folder 3)
      - Struve, William, Consultant, 1995 (Box 82, Folder 4)
    - University Centers, 1964-1966 (Box 30, Folder 40)
    - University Committee, 1969-1983 (Box 30, Folder 42-42)
    - University Extension
      - 1972-1984 (Box 31, Folder 1-7)
      - Off-Campus Instructional Program, 1973-1984 (Box 31, Folder 8-13)
      - Writing Program for Adults, 1981-1982 (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - Urban Planning MS, 1972-1975 (Box 31, Folder 15-21)
    - Urban Social Institutions
      - 1977, undated (Box 63, Folder 3)
      - Doctoral Program, Planning Document
        - 1982 (Box 63, Folder 4)
        - 1983 (Box 59, Folder 4)
      - Five-Year Graduate Program Review, 1981 (Box 63, Folder 5)
      - Steering Committee, 1976-1982 (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Urban Social Institutions PhD, 1976 (Box 31, Folder 22)
    - Urbanism: Past and Present, 1980-1985 (Box 31, Folder 23)
    - UW System Liberal Arts Deans, 1972-1977 (Box 31, Folder 24-25)
    - UW System, Working Group on Basic Competencies, Madison, 1989 (Box 82, Folder 5)
    - UWM Parents' and Friends Association, 1977-1978 (Box 31, Folder 26)
    - Vice Chancellor
      - 1959-1964 (Box 31, Folder 27-30)
      - 1965-1981 (Box 32, Folder 1-29)
      - 1982 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Vilas Professorship, 1966-1970 (Box 33, Folder 2-3)
    - Walters, William L., 1968 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Washington Center for Learning Alternatives Program, 1976-1985 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Waukesha Cooperative Program, 1982 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Where to from Here?: Majors in the College of Letters and Science, 1974-1981 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Wisconsin Center for Research on Language, 1984-1986 (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - Wisconsin Legislature, Select Committee on the Future of the UW System, 1985 (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Women, 1970-1973 (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Women's Studies, 1972-1983, 2002 (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - Women's Studies, Academic Planning Document, 1982-1983 (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - WUWM
      - 1970-1983 (Box 33, Folder 12-30)
      - 1983-1992 (Box 59, Folder 6)
      - 1984-1986 (Box 34, Folder 1-5)
      - Black Community, 1977-1979 (Box 34, Folder 6-7)
      - Cancellation of Salsa y Bembe, 1983 (Box 35, Folder 1)
      - Community Advisory Board, 1983-1986 (Box 35, Folder 2)
      - Satellite Connection, 1977-1979 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Year 2000 Master Plan Committee, 1982 (Box 83, Folder 22)
    - Zablocki Institute, 1986 (Box 59, Folder 7)
  - 2. Publicity Files, 1970-2009
    - Photographs, 1996-2001
      - Ads, 1996, undated (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - Advisors, 1997-1999, undated (Box 83, Folder 2)
      - Alumni, 1996, undated (Box 83, Folder 3)
      - Alumni College, 1999-2000 (Box 83, Folder 4)
      - Campus Life, 1996-1999, undated (Box 83, Folder 5)
      - Dean/Chancellor, 1996-1998, undated (Box 83, Folder 6)
      - Departments, 1997-1999, undated (Box 83, Folder 7)
      - Events, 1996-2000, undated (Box 83, Folder 8)
      - Faculty, undated (Box 83, Folder 9-11)
      - New Directions Awards Ceremony, 1997-2001 undated (Box 83, Folder 12)
    - Publications, 1970-2009
      - L & S Magazine, 1983 (Box 21, Folder 30)
      - L & S Update, 1989-1995 (Box 83, Folder 17)
      - L & S Works! Research Review, 1997 (Box 78, Folder 4)
      - L & SA (Letters & Science Alumni), 1997 (Box 78, Folder 3)
      - Letters and Science Review, 1998-2009 (Box 83, Folder 13)
      - LS Scholastic Affairs Newsletter, 1970-1982 (Box 22, Folder 30)
- Personnel Files, 1965-1998, Accession 2002-071; 0.8 cubic ft. (2 boxes); Official personnel files of faculty and unclassified staff who retired during this period. The personnel files are mostly from the Philosophy Department.
- Personnel Files, 1956-2009, Accession 2009-063; 3 cubic ft. (3 boxes); Additional personnel files closed between 2000 and 2009, with dates of employment between 1956-2009.
- Personnel Files, 1997, Accession 2010-068(2); 2 folders; Additional personnel files from the Dept. of Psychology closed in 1997.
- Personnel Files, 1964-2013, Accession 2013-011; 3 cubic ft. (3 boxes); Additional personnel files dating from 1964 to 2013.
- Personnel Files, 1960-2011, Accession 2016-003; 3 cubic ft. (3 boxes); Additional personnel files dating from 1960-2011.
- Subject and Personnel Files, 1968-2013, Accession 2016-032; 13.2 cubic ft. (15 boxes); Subject, planning, and personnel files from the College of Letters and Sciences Office of the Dean. The accession includes budget information, records from the Center of International Studies, Diversity Assessment Workbooks, records from the Latin America Center, financial information concerning the Milwaukee Graduate Assistants Assoication (MGAA), and personnel awards. Of particular interest in the subject files are records on the origin of the Law Studies Program and several quality reinvestiment plans. A large portion of the accession is meeting minutes from college committees, department committees, staff, and faculty.
  - Academic Staff Meetings, 1992-1993 (Box 1)
  - Academic Staff Professional Development Program, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Ad Hoc Committees, 1997-2001 (Box 1)
  - Affirmative Action Data-Monitoring, 1992-1993 (Box 1)
  - Affirmative Action Evaluation of Deans and Administrators, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Africology Faculty Annual Summaries, 2005 (Box 1)
  - Allocations, 1992-1993 (Box 1)
  - Annual Report, Natural Sciences, 2004 (Box 1)
  - Anthropology Faculty Annual Summaries, 2005 (Box 1)
  - Basketball Game, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Benefits Office, 1995-2002 (Box 1)
  - Biological Sciences Faculty Annual Summaries, 2005 (Box 1)
  - Brown Bag Speakers, 1996-1997 (Box 1)
  - Budget, 1988-2004 (Box 1)
  - Budget Lapse, 1992-1993 (Box 1)
  - Budget Meeting with Provost, 2005 (Box 1)
  - Budget Meeting with Provost, 2007, 2010 (Box 1)
  - Budget Planning and Affirmative Action, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Building Manager, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Business and Financial Services, 1995-1996 (Box 1)
  - Career Tracking for Diversity Compliance, 1998-1999 (Box 1)
  - Center for International Studies
    - Budget, 1992-1993 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence, 1991-1995 (Box 1)
    - Grants and Awards, 1991-1997 (Box 2)
    - Occasional Papers, 1993-1995 (Box 2)
  - Chairs' Training, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Chancellor Correspondence, 1995-1997 (Box 2)
  - Chemistry and Biochemistry Faculty Annual Summaries, 2005 (Box 2)
  - Chemistry Staffing Plans, 2002-2003 (Box 2)
  - Classified Outstanding Service Awards, 2000-2004 (Box 2)
  - Classified Service Reform Proposal, 1996 (Box 2)
  - Classified Staff Correspondence, 1993 (Box 2)
  - ColdFusion, 2001-2002 (Box 2)
  - Comprehensive National Resource Center and Foreign Language and Area Studies Fellowship, 2002-2003 (Box 2)
  - Department Chairs Meetings, 1995-2003 (Box 2)
  - Department of Employee Relations, 1992-1993 (Box 2)
  - Diversity Assessment Workbook, 1995-2004 (Box 2)
  - Economics Faculty Annual Summaries, 2005 (Box 2)
  - Employee Assistance Program, 1992-1993 (Box 3)
  - Equity Award, 1992-1993 (Box 3)
  - Exceptional Performance Awards, 1992-1996 (Box 3)
  - Faculty Development Plans, 1989-1993 (Box 3)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1986-2005 (Box 3)
  - Faculty and Staff Development Program Guidelines, 1995-1997 (Box 3)
  - Faculty Salary Equity Study, 1993 (Box 3)
  - Faculty Workload Audit, 1992-1993 (Box 3)
  - First Friday, 1996 (Box 3)
  - Foreign Language Departments Merger, 1995-1996 (Box 3)
  - Fringe Benefit Rates for Extramural Support Funds, 1992-2001 (Box 3)
  - Gay and Lesbian Studies Certificate Program, 1993-2002 (Box 3)
  - Gender Equity Project, 1990-1995 (Box 3)
  - Geography Faculty Annual Summaries, 2005 (Box 3)
  - Geosciences Faculty Annual Summaries, 2005 (Box 3)
  - Goals, 2002-2003 (Box 3)
  - Goodman Correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box 3)
  - History Faculty Annual Summaries, 2005 (Box 3)
  - Horstman Meetings, 1995-2002 (Box 3)
  - Human Resources Correspondence, 1995-2003 (Box 3)
  - Information Technology Survey, 1992-2003 (Box 3)
  - International Relations Major, 1990-1993 (Box 3)
  - International Relations Major Title VI, 1990 (Box 3)
  - Journalism and Mass Communication Faculty Annual Summaries, 2005 (Box 3)
  - Labor Management Minutes, 1992-2004 (Box 3)
  - Labor Relations, 1992-1996 (Box 4)
  - Language and Literature Advisory Committee Meetings, 1981-1996 (Box 4)
  - Language Resource Center, 1990-2003 (Box 4)
  - Latin America Center
    - Advisory Committee, 1989-2008 (Box 4)
    - Budget, 1983-1996 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, 1968-2010 (Box 4)
    - General Grant Information, 1984-2004 (Box 4)
    - Internal Review, 1993 (Box 4)
  - Lawson (Kronos Project), 2001-2002 (Box 4)
  - Limited Term Employees Review Team, 1991-1993 (Box 4)
  - Material Handling Staff Personnel Management Survey, 1991-1993 (Box 4)
  - Mathematical Sciences Faculty Annual Surveys, 2005 (Box 4)
  - Media Technician Study, 1994-1996 (Box 4)
  - Meeting Minutes, 2006-2012 (Box 8-10)
    The meeting minutes in boxes 8-10 are unprocessed handwritten records, created by the Dean or the Dean's Assistant, placed in pocket folders and arranged by year. Several committees are represented. The records provide additional context to the happenings in the meetings not described in the official minutes.
  - Military Leave, 2001-2002 (Box 4)
  - Milwaukee Commitment Report, 2001-2002 (Box 4)
  - Milwaukee Graduate Assistants Association Agreement, 1991-2005 (Box 4)
  - Non-represented Classified Employment Compensation, 1995-1996 (Box 4)
  - Office of Diversity/Compliance Concilliation Agreement, 1995-1996 (Box 4)
  - Office Support Exam Development, 1993-1996 (Box 5)
  - Pay Plan, 1995-2001 (Box 5)
  - Performance Appraisal Classified Staff, 1992-2002 (Box 5)
  - Personnel Action Deadlines, 1989-1996 (Box 5)
  - Personnel Representatives Meetings, 1995-2004 (Box 5)
  - Physics Faculty Annual Summaries, 2005 (Box 5)
  - Planning Document, 2004 (Box 5)
  - Plan 2008 Report, 2003 (Box 5)
  - Political Science Faculty Annual Summaries, 2005 (Box 5)
  - Proposal for Undergraduate Law Studies Program, 1972-1988 (Box 5)
  - Psychology Faculty Annual Summaries, 2005 (Box 5)
  - Quality Reinvestment Plan, 1991-1994 (Box 6)
  - Recruitment Correspondence, 2009-2013 (Box 6)
  - Research Growth Initiative Awards, 2009-2010 (Box 6)
  - Salary Adjustments Guidelines, 1989-1992 and 2001-2002 (Box 7)
  - Service Designation Review, 1992-1993 (Box 7)
  - Sociology Faculty Annual Summaries, 2005 (Box 7)
  - Spring Awards Picnic, 1997 (Box 7)
  - Staff Development Programs, 1992-1993 (Box 7)
  - Student and Multicultural Affairs Reorganization Plan, 2003 (Box 7)
  - Wisconsin Association of Black State State Employees Conference, 1995-1996 (Box 7)
  - Wisconsin State Department of Administration Required Budget Lapse, 1992-1993 (Box 7)
  - Wisconsin Legislative Updates, 1989 (Box 7)